<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Atlantis</string>
    <string name="title_activity_second">SecondActivity</string>
    <string name="tab_text_1">Login</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">Sign up</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>

    <!-- Historias Marcos -->
    <string name="historia_tortuga">
        Turtles are reptiles. The most characteristic feature of turtles is their shell. It helps them defend themselves against their predators, but it is not as strong as you think.
        It is composed of 50 bones, nerves, cartilage and blood supply. If their shell is damaged, turtles feel pain and can bleed.
        The back and front legs, the head and the tail come out of the shell.\n \n

        Most are omnivores. Their diet is basically based on: fish, algae, molluscs, crustaceans, corals, plants and marine sponges.\n \n

        Turtles live mainly in tropical and subtropical seas around the planet, they like warm waters, temperatures higher than 20º.\n \n

        They can live more than 100 years. It varies a bit depending on the species. It is also not possible to know exactly since the veterinarians/biologists
        Marines do not have much control over them, due to the great migrations they make.\n \n

        All species of sea turtles are in danger of extinction or are vulnerable to becoming so soon. The main threats are
        the fishing nets that trap them, the destruction of their habitat by dirt or climate change.\n \n
    </string>
    <string name="historia_coral">
        A reef is a large group of rocks at the bottom of the ocean. Do you know that a reef is really alive and covered with
        very small animals called corals? These animals glue their tiny skeletons to rocks, making their own
        houses, so they end up staying in the same place all their lives.\n \n

        They are rarely found alone, as they congregate with many other corals forming what are known as colonies or sea forests.
        As in the jungle, reefs are one of the most diverse ecosystems on earth, where almost a quarter of the
        marine species, such as fish, starfish, crabs, clams, sea snakes, etc.\n \n

        Coral reefs are very fragile ecosystems, in part because of their sensitivity to changes in water temperature.
        They are endangered by climate change, ocean acidification and water pollution. If the coral reefs
        they are under a lot of stress, they can expel the algae that live in them and turn completely white. This does not necessarily mean
        that the coral is dead, although it becomes more vulnerable to death, especially if the stress continues for a long period of time.\n \n

        They can be differentiated depending on how they get food. Photosynthetic corals need sunlight to get food. The rest of the corals obtain food by trapping plankton.\n \n

        That is why corals require sunlight and grow in clear, shallow water, usually at depths less than 60 meters.\n \n

        The longest reef is the Great Barrier Reef, off the coast of Queensland in Australia: it is more than 2000 km.\n \n
    </string>
    <string name="historia_pez">
        The puffer fish developed its famous ability to inflate itself due to its slow and clumsy swimming style. That makes them vulnerable to predators.
        Instead of escaping, pufferfish use their highly elastic stomach and ability to quickly take in large amounts of water (and even air if necessary).
        so that it becomes a practically unbelievable ball that doubles several times its normal size. Some species also have spines on their skin to avoid being eaten.\n \n

        A predator that manages to catch a puffer fish before it inflates will not feel lucky for long. Almost all puffer fish contain a toxin, which causes
        puffer fish have a very unpleasant taste, often lethal to fish. For humans it is also very dangerous being one of the most toxic poisons and that still does not have
        antidote.\n \n

        Most are found in tropical and subtropical ocean waters, but some species live in fresh and brackish waters.\n \n

        Their size varies, from the 1-inch-long dwarf puffer fish to the giant freshwater puffer fish, which can grow up to more than 61 centimeters in length.\n \n

        The diet of the puffer fish includes mainly invertebrate animals and algae. Larger specimens can even crack open shells with their hard beak and eat clams, mussels, and shellfish.\n \n
    </string>
    <string name="historia_anemona">
        Anemones are pink, plant-like invertebrates with long, wriggling tentacles. Anemones can have two different shapes.
        A smaller form, 2-5 cm in diameter, living on well-lit rock faces and blocky bottoms down to 5 m depth. On the other hand, the other is larger, up to 15 cm in length.
        diameter and with 50 cm tentacles live in the same situations but at greater depths.\n \n

        The sea anemone can be very stinging. When touched with the fingers, the stinging cells attack the skin, but without piercing it, and the tentacles remain attached to the fingers. like the tentacles
        they come off easily, there is always a danger that they will reach more delicate areas, such as the face, neck, the inside of the arms, etc., causing injuries.\n \n

        They are usually found in shallow and calm waters such as bays, they also support the dirt of the water. They are found in the Mediterranean Sea.\n \n
    </string>

    <!-- Historias Miguel -->
    <string name="historia_tiburon">
        The frilled shark is considered a living fossil, because of its primitive, anguilliform (eel-like) physical traits, such as a dark-brown color, amphistyly (the articulation of the jaws to the cranium), and a 2.0 m long body, which has dorsal, pelvic, and anal fins located towards the tail. The common name, frilled shark, derives from the fringed appearance of the six pairs of gill slits at the shark\'s throat. \n\n
		The two species of frilled shark are distributed throughout regions of the Atlantic and the Pacific oceans, usually in the waters of the outer continental shelf and of the upper continental slope, where the sharks usually live near the ocean floor, near biologically productive areas of the ecosystem. \n To live on a diet of cephalopods, smaller sharks, and bony fish, the frilled shark practices diel vertical migration to feed at night at the surface of the ocean. \n When hunting food, the frilled shark moves like an eel, bending and lunging to capture and swallow whole prey with its long and flexible jaws, which are equipped with 300 recurved, needle-like teeth. \n\n
		Reproductively, the gestation period of the frilled shark can be up to 3.5 years long, to produce a litter of 2–15 shark pups. \n Usually caught as bycatch in commercial fishing, the frilled shark has some economic value as a meat and as fishmeal; and has been caught from depths of 1,570 m, although its occurrence is uncommon below 1,200 m ; whereas in Suruga Bay, Japan, the frilled shark commonly occurs at depths of 50 to 200 m. \n\n
		The frilled shark eats a diet of cephalopods, sea slugs, smaller sharks, and bony fish. \n\n
		The frilled shark is a predator with long jaws directly articulated to the cranium, at a point behind the eyes. \n\n
		In hunting and eating prey that are tired or exhausted or dying (after spawn),the frilled shark\'s physiology suggests that it may curve its anguilline body, and brace its rear fins against the water, for leverage to effect a rapid-strike bite that captures the prey. \n The wide gape of the distended, long jaws allows devouring whole prey that are more than half the size of the frilled shark, itself. \n The jaws\' 300 recurved teeth (19–28 upper rows and 21–29 lower rows) readily snag and capture the soft body and tentacles of a cephalopod, especially with the rows of trident-shaped teeth are rotated outwards, when the jaws are open and protruded. \n Moreover, unlike the strong bite of sharks with an underslung jaw attached below the cranium,[28] the frilled shark has a relatively weak bite, because of the limited leverage and force possible with long jaws that are directly articulated to the cranium, at a point behind the eyes. \n\n
		The behavior of captive specimen sharks suggests that the frilled shark also hunts with its mouth open, by using the dark-and-light contrast of white teeth and darkness to lure prey into its gaping maw; and also hunts with negative pressure, to suck prey into its maw. \n Forensic examination of frilled sharks\' revealed little-to-no food in their stomachs, which suggests that the frilled shark either has a fast-rate of digestion or goes hungry in the long intervals between feedings.

    </string>
    <string name="historia_ballena">
       The blue whale (Balaenoptera musculus) is a marine mammal and a baleen whale. \n Reaching a maximum confirmed length of 29.9 meters and weighing up to 199 metric tons (196 long tons; 219 short tons), it is the largest animal known to have ever existed. \n The blue whale\'s long and slender body can be of various shades of greyish-blue dorsally and somewhat lighter underneath. \n\n
       The blue whale is the largest known animal to have ever existed. \n The International Whaling Commission whaling database reports 88 individuals longer than 30 meters, including one of 33 meters. \n\n
       Blue whales are generally solitary or gather in small groups and have no well-defined social structure other than mother-calf bonds. \n\n
       The blue whale was once abundant in nearly all the \'s oceans until the end of the 19th century. \n It was hunted almost to the point of extinction by whalers until the International Whaling Commission banned all blue whale hunting in 1966. \n The International Union for Conservation of Nature has listed blue whales as endangered as of 2018. \n It continues to face numerous threats, both man-made (ship strikes, pollution, ocean noise and climate change) and natural (killer whale predation). \n\n
       The blue whale\'s diet consists almost exclusively of krill. \n They feed on these organisms at depths ranging from 200 meters to the surface, following their prey\'s 24 hour migration up the water column. \n Blue whales capture krill through lunge feeding, they swim towards them at high speeds with the mouth wide open. \n They may engulf 220 metric tons (220 long tons; 240 short tons) of water at one time. \n They squeeze the water out through their baleen plates with pressure from the throat pouch and tongue, and swallow the remaining krill. \n Blue whales have been recorded making 180° rolls during lunge-feeding, allowing them to engulf krill patches while inverted. \n They rolled while searching for prey between lunges, which has been hypothesized as allowing them to survey the prey field and find the densest patches. \n\n

    </string>
    <string name="historia_narval">
        The narwhal, is a medium-sized toothed whale that possesses a large "tusk" from a protruding canine tooth. \n It lives year-round in the Arctic waters around Greenland, Canada and Russia. \n The narwhal males are distinguished by a long, straight, helical tusk, which is an elongated upper left canine. \n\n
        Like the beluga, narwhals are medium-sized whales. \n For both sexes, excluding the male\'s tusk, the total body size can range from 3.95 to 5.5 m; the males are slightly larger than the females. \n The average weight of an adult narwhal is 800 to 1,600 kg. \n At around 11 to 13 years old, the males become sexually mature; females become sexually mature at about 5 to 8 years old. \n Narwhals do not have a dorsal fin and their neck vertebrae are jointed like those of most other mammals, not fused as in dolphins and most whales. \n\n
        Found primarily in Canadian Arctic and Greenlandic and Russian waters, the narwhal is a uniquely specialised Arctic predator. \n In winter, it feeds on benthic prey, mostly flatfish, under dense pack ice. \n During the summer, narwhals eat mostly Arctic cod and Greenland halibut, with other fish such as polar cod making up the remainder of their diet. \n Each year, they migrate from bays into the ocean as summer comes. \n In the winter, the male narwhals occasionally dive up to 1,500 m in depth, with dives lasting up to 25 minutes. \n Narwhals, like most toothed whales, communicate with "clicks", "whistles" and "knocks". \n\n
        Narwhals are often killed by suffocation after being trapped due to the formation of sea ice. \n Other causes of death, specifically among young whales, are starvation and predation by orcas. \n As previous estimates of the world narwhal population were below 50,000, narwhals are categorised by the International Union for Conservation of Nature as "nearly threatened". \n More recent estimates list higher populations (upwards of 170,000), thus lowering the status to "least concern". \n Narwhals have been harvested for hundreds of years by Inuit people in northern Canada and Greenland for meat and ivory and a regulated subsistence hunt continues. \n\n
        Narwhals can live an average of 50 years, however research suggests that narwhals can live to be as old as 115 years and 84 years for females and males, respectively.
    </string>
    <string name="historia_foca">
		The earless seals, phocids or true seals are one of the three main groups of mammals within the seal lineage, Pinnipedia. \n All true seals are members of the family Phocidae. \n They are sometimes called crawling seals to distinguish them from the fur seals and sea lions of the family Otariidae. \n Seals live in the oceans of both hemispheres and, with the exception of the more tropical monk seals, are mostly confined to polar, subpolar, and temperate climates. \n\n
        Adult phocids vary from 1.17 m  in length and 45 kg  in weight in the ringed seal to 5.8 mand 4,000 kg in the southern elephant sheal. \n\n
		Phocids are known for efficient, economical movement. \n This allows most phocids to forage far from land to exploit prey resources, while otariids are tied to rich upwelling zones close to breeding sites. \n Phocids swim by sideways movements of their bodies, using their hind flippers to fullest effect.Their fore flippers are used primarily for steering, while their hind flippers are bound to the pelvis in such a way that they cannot bring them under their bodies to walk on them. \n They are more streamlined than fur seals and sea lions, so they can swim more effectively over long distances. \n However, because they cannot turn their hind flippers downward, they are very clumsy on land, having to wriggle with their front flippers and abdominal muscles. \n\n
		Phocid respiratory and circulatory systems are adapted to allow diving to considerable depths, and they can spend a long time underwater between breaths. \n Air is forced from the lungs during a dive and into the upper respiratory passages, where gases cannot easily be absorbed into the bloodstream. \n This helps protect the seal from the bends. \n The middle ear is also lined with blood sinuses that inflate during diving, helping to maintain a constant pressure. \n\n
		Phocids are more specialized for aquatic life than otariids. They lack external ears and have sleek, streamlined bodies. Retractable nipples, internal testicles,[16] and an internal penile sheath provide further streamlining. \n A smooth layer of blubber lies underneath the skin. \n Phocids are able to divert blood flow to this layer to help control their temperatures. \n\n
		Phocids make use of at least four different feeding strategies: suction feeding, grip, and tear feeding, filter feeding, and pierce feeding. \n Each of these feeding strategies is aided by a specialized skull, mandible, and tooth morphology. \n However, despite morphological specialization, most phocids are opportunistic and employ multiple strategies to capture and eat prey. \n For example, the leopard seal, uses grip and tear feeding to prey on penguins, suction feeding to consume small fish, and filter feeding to catch krill. \n\n

    </string>

    <!-- Historias Sergio -->
    <string name="historia_ajolote">
        Among the extraordinary Mexican fauna there is an amazing species, the Mexican axolotl (Ambystoma mexicanum).
        It has an unusual physical appearance, it\'s the possessor of extraordinary faculties:
        It has the exceptional capacity to regenerate lost organs,
        and even part of the brain!… and the heart! \n \n

        The native and endemic axolotl (lives only) of the lakes of the Valley of Mexico and survives in Lake Xochimilco,
        It was called by the ancient Mexicans axolotl (from Nahuatl, "water monster") and retains ancient characteristics of
        salamanders, but is closer to frogs and toads.\n \n

        However, it seems to have forgotten his ability to move on land, because although he has four legs that
        allow him walking, in addition to a tail that it retains after metamorphosis (transformation),
        it only rises to the surface of the lake to breathe and immediately submerges.\n \n

        Black or mottled brown, albino or white, the Mexican axolotl retains its tadpole dorsal fin that extends almost
        throughout its entire body, which measures from 15 to 30 centimeters in length, and its external gills are
        shaped like feathers protrude from the back of its broad head.\n \n

        This axolotl feeds on molluscs, worms, larvae, crustaceans and the occasional fish, but it has not been able to
        get rid of the herons (type of bird) that engulf him and even less of its main predator, the human,
        who has also introduced large fish to Lake Xochimilco and its channels that threaten its survival.\n \n

        From before the Colony to the present, the axolotl has been a highly appreciated food for its flavor and
        nutritional properties, the same prepared in tamales as in soups and stews, that used in traditional medicine
        in formulas of syrup, ointment or infusions, against respiratory ailments.\n \n

        So many virtues made this unique creature was taken to the danger of extinction, because most citizens
        ignore that the repopulation of the Mexican axolotl is necessary,
        the same as stopping the degradation of its lacustrine habitat (lake where it lives).
    </string>
    <string name="historia_caballito">
        Seahorses attract attention. Its horse appearance in the body of a fish is the origin of its name.
        Thousands of euros can be paid for the most showy species and in some parts of the planet they are in
        danger for its medicinal uses in some countries. In the south of Portugal, the world\'s largest population, was
        located of seahorses. In a very small space, 600,000 specimens of two species lived, now there are only 155,000 left.
        They are now in danger of extinction. \n \n

        Seahorses are fish. However, they are different from other fish, as they have a flexible neck,
        a snout and a nimble tail. They can move each eye independently. The seahorse\'s tail is
        organized in square prisms, surrounded by bony plates.
        They use their tails as anchors.
        Its shape resists damage better and has a better grip than if it were circular.
        They usually live between 4 to 6 years. They live among corals, macroalgae, phanerogams (seed plants)
        marine and mangroves.\n \n

        They have no teeth or stomachs. They suck their prey whole up to 3 cm away.
        Because they lack stomachs, seahorses have to eat most of the time because of the rapid process of
        digestion. And as quickly as it eats, it defecates. They feed on small crustaceans, invertebrates and fishe\'s larvae.
        And its main food in the aquarium is Artemia, a small crustacean.
        A seahorse can eat 3,000 brine shrimp a day. \n\n

        Some seahorses are capable of changing color to blend in with their surroundings.
        The seahorses\' best defense against predators is camouflage.
        The males often fight each other with their tails during the mating season.
        The females also fight with each other or with other males, fighting for territory or food. \n \n

        In pairs, seahorses swim together holding on to each other\'s tails.
        Before mating, they perform a dance that culminates in the fertilization of the female\'s oocytes and the
        which the male shelters in the ventral area. They will stay there until the little ones are ready to leave.
        Then come the muscular contractions and the expulsion of their little ones.
        A male horse has to go through 45 days of pregnancy and can have 1,500 or even 1,800 offspring.
        Very few larvae reach the adult stage (1%). \n\n

        There are about 50 different species of seahorses.
        The smallest species is Hippocampus japapigu, this species is about 15 millimeters long.
        The largest species is Hippocampus ingens. Males can be 30 centimeters long.
    </string>
    <string name="historia_langosta">
        It is a decapod crustacean (it has 10 legs). It lives on rocky bottoms that are not too deep and usually less than
        100 m. hidden among the rocks. It can rarely be found on rocky bottoms (which have many stones).
        They are related to river crabs. They weigh between 700 grams and 7 kilos and their dimension can be between 25 and
        50 cm. \n \n

        Despite its heavy appearance, it is able to swim thanks to the powerful contractions of its heavily muscled tail.
        This is the part that makes it highly appreciated gastronomically. \n

        Of nocturnal habits, the lobster is very voracious and feeds on everything it finds, although its preferences are
        focus on polychaetes (worms), crustaceans, molluscs, algae, organic debris and worms. It highlights the fact that it is
        capable of breaking the hard shells of bivalves, despite lacking tweezers. \n \n

        According to the Book of Records, the largest lobster was caught in Nova Scotia (Canada), weighing 20.14 kg. \n
        When the lobster grows, it must shed the hard calcified shell that covers it (this operation is carried out several
        times throughout his life). It is precisely when it sheds its old armor that the animal is very vulnerable,
        since the new shell does not harden until after a few hours. This exoskeleton is often eaten by
        lobster to replenish the body\'s calcium reserves. \n \n

        The locust uses its long antennae to drive away its enemies, putting them between itself and the intruder.
        He also uses them to learn his immediate surroundings through touch, a necessary skill in low-light conditions.
        lighting typical of the cracks and holes in which you live. \n \n

        During their migration or journey, the locusts form a line touching the tail of the locust with their antennae.
        in front. Lobsters can form rows of up to 100,000 individuals, the row has the appearance of an eel
        or gigantic snake. If a daring animal tries to attack them, the locusts form a circle with their tails facing
        the center and all its spines out. \n \n
    </string>
    <string name="historia_lobo">
        The appearance of this species varies more than that of any other family with age and sex.
        Adult males have a very long neck covered with thick and thick fur in relation to the rest of the body.
        Its snout is short and raised, adorned with long whiskers. \n \n

        The total length of the animal can reach up to 3.50 meters. The females do not exceed 2.50 meters,
        their forms are slim and elegant, the neck does not acquire the same thickness as that of the males and they lack a mane. \n \n

        The cubs, at birth, measure just over 40 cm. and are covered in short, healthy-looking hair that is almost black in color.\n \n

        Sea lions spend almost all their time in the sea. They are very skilled in the water, when they come out on land,
        look for the loneliest rocks or islets and walk with the body raised on the 4 limbs,
        with clumsy movements, but quite fast. Their food consists exclusively of fish.
        They devour between 15 and 25 kg per day. \n \n

        When spring arrives they begin to gather in the sea lion colonies; males arrive first
        They spend almost the whole day on land and soon after the females arrive to give birth.
        For a period of about 5 weeks these animals do not go to the water and therefore do not eat.
        The males form their harems, fighting with each other to see which can bring together the largest number of females.
        Everything is a continuous movement and it is also the moment where the killer whales approach to obtain their precious prey,
        pup wolves…
    </string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="volver_a_historia">Back to story selection</string>
    <string name="respuestas_incorrectas">Incorrects answers: 0</string>
    <string name="respuestas_correctas">Corrects answers : 0</string>
    <string name="test_completado">You have completed the quiz!</string>
    <string name="elige_una_historia">Choose an story</string>
    <string name="caballito_de_mar">Seahorse</string>
    <string name="ballena_azul">Blue whale</string>
    <string name="ajolote">Axolotl</string>
    <string name="tortuga_marina">Sea turtle</string>
    <string name="coral">Coral</string>
    <string name="pez_globo">Puffer fish</string>
    <string name="anemona_de_mar">Sea anemone</string>
    <string name="langosta">Lobster</string>
    <string name="lobo_marino">Sea wolf</string>
    <string name="foca">Seal</string>
    <string name="tiburon_anguila">Frilled shark</string>
    <string name="narval">Narwhal</string>
    <string name="selecciona_la_respuesta_correcta">Select the correct answer</string>
    <string name="aqui_ira_la_pregunta">Here goes the question…</string>
    <string name="_00_59">00:59</string>
    <string name="primera_opcion">First option</string>
    <string name="segunda_opcion">Second option</string>
    <string name="tercera_opcion">Third option</string>
    <string name="cuarta_opcion">Forth option</string>
    <string name="siguiente">Next</string>
    <string name="usuario">User</string>
    <string name="contrasenia">Password</string>
    <string name="entrar">Login</string>
    <string name="crear">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="a">A</string>
    <string name="t">T</string>
    <string name="terminos_y_condiciones">I accept the terms and conditions and the privacy notice</string>
    <string name="l">L</string>
    <string name="n">N</string>
    <string name="i">I</string>
    <string name="s">S</string>
    <string name="volver">Back</string>
    <string name="NoTienesCuenta">Don\'t you have an account? Swipe to the left</string>
    <string name="cambiar_tema">Change theme</string>
    <string name="descripcion_alga_roja">Image of a red algae</string>
    <string name="descripcion_alga_verde1">First image of a green algae</string>
    <string name="descripcion_alga_verde2">Second image of a green algae</string>
    <string name="descripcion_boton_back">Image of a button that let us going back</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_caballito">Image of a seahorse</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_tortuga">Image of a sea turtle</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_ballena">Image of a blue whale</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_coral">Image of a coral</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_langosta">Image of a lobster</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_lobo_marino">Image of a sea wolf</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_pez_globo">Image of a puffer fish</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_narval">Image of a narwhal</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_anemona">Image of a sea anemone</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_tiburon">Image of a frilled shark</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_foca">Image of a seal</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_crono">Image of the chrone we use in the quiz</string>
    <string name="descripcion_fab">Floating action button that let us go into the quiz</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_ajolote_ss">Imagen of an axolotl which we use in the Splash Screen</string>
    <string name="descripcion_pompa">Bubble we use in the Splash Screen</string>
    <string name="descripcion_alga_verde3">Third image of a green algae</string>
    <string name="descripcion_imagen_ajolote">Image of an axolotl</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="elige_respuesta">Please, select an answer</string>
    <string name="loginCompletado">Login succesfully</string>
    <string name="loginError">Error with the login</string>
    <string name="Entrando">Entering…</string>
    <string name="EsperandoRegistro">Waiting to complete the register</string>
    <string name="Registro">Register</string>
    <string name="registroCompletado">Register succesfully</string>
    <string name="errorRegistro">Error in the register</string>
    <string name="tiempo">Time is over!</string>
    <string name="quiz_terminado">Submit quiz!</string>
</resources>